变种人
Mutants...
生来即天赋异禀
born with extraordinary abilities...
话虽如此 但他们尚属稚嫩在黑暗中为摸索方向
and yet, still, they are children stumbling in the dark...
而步履蹒跚
searching for guidance.
天赋 往往也会是个诅咒
A gift can often be a curse.
拥有一双翅膀 他可能直扑太阳而去
Give someone wings, and they may fly too close to the sun.
给他预知未来的力量
Give them the power of prophecy...
他就可能活在对未来的恐惧当中
and they may live in fear of the future.
若给予一个人所有的天赋
Give them the greatest gifts of all...
超乎想像的巨大力量
powers beyond imagination...
他就可能试图统治整个世界
and they may think they're meant to rule the world.
(纪元前3600年  尼罗河谷)
恩·沙巴·奴尔
En Sabah Nur.
现在你将永远统治这个世界了 主人
Now you will rule for eternity, my lord.
沉睡吧
Sleep.
开始移转
Let the transference begin.
伪神受死吧
Death to the false god.
保护好主人
Protect him!
《X战警：天启》
众所周知 变种人的存在首次被发现
As everyone knows, the existence of mutants was first discovered...
是在1973年越战结束后的巴黎和会期间
during the Paris Peace Accords, after the Vietnam War in 1973.
6天后 我们亲眼目睹一名变种人…
Six days later, we all watched as one of those mutants...
艾瑞克·兰谢尔在白宫的草坪上
Erik Lehnsherr, attacked the President...
攻击总统和他的内阁成员
and the Cabinet on the lawn of the White House.
一位年轻的女变种人阻止了他
Their lives were saved by a young mutant who stopped him.
兰谢尔逃脱并成为世界头号通缉犯
Now, Lehnsherr escaped and became the world's most-wanted fugitive.
至于她 从此销声匿迹
And as for her, she disappeared as well.
但她已经成为这个新时代的典范
But she has become the symbol of a new age...
而这个世界的面貌自此完全改观
the face of a world that will never be the same again.
你是在跟我女友抛媚眼吗？
You winking at my girl?
你女友
Your girl?
那你看来也太老气了 当她老爸刚好
I guess you do look old enough to be her father.
很抱歉 同学
Excuse me, gentlemen...
有什么事情想要 和班上其他同学分享的么？
is there something you'd like to share with the rest of the class?
我能去趟洗手间吗
Can I please go to the bathroom?
我的眼睛非常不舒服
I think there's something seriously wrong with my eyes.
好吧 史考特 在那之后
Fine, Scott. And afterwards...
请你顺道 拜访校长跟他解释一下
why don't you stop by the principal's office and explain to him...
你为什么上课捣乱
that you're disrupting class again?
我相信你认得路
I trust you know the way.
- 是的 - 很好
- Yeah, I do. - Okay.
哦 别急 别急
No, hang on! Hang on!
嘿
Hey!
我知道你们大多数
Now, I know most of you were, what?
那时候7岁左右吧
Around seven years old at that time?
桑莫斯
Summers!
我知道你在里面
I know you're in here.
你在哭吗？
What, are you crying?
我还没动手修理你
I haven't even kicked your ass yet.
桑莫斯. 这么喜欢盯着我女友看？
Summers! You want to eyeball my girl?
(东柏林)
耶
Yeah!
10战
Ten fights waged.
10胜
Ten fights won.
翼战士
The Winged Warrior.
猛禽
The Bird of Prey.
死亡天使
The Angel of Death.
天使
Angel!
耶
Yeah!
给胖哥来点掌声鼓励
Let's hear it for the fat man!
下一位挑战者
Our next challenger...
来自…
comes straight...
慕尼黑马戏团
from the Munich Circus.
(第11场决斗)
各为女士先生
Ladies and gentlemen,
敢于挑战天使…
the only one that could take on an Angel...
必然就是恶魔
is the Devil himself.
隆重介绍…
I give you...
惊人的…
the amazing...
神奇的…
the fantastic...
夜行者
Nightcrawler!
警告
Caution
有高压电
High voltage!
很抱歉 变种人
Sorry mutants!
嘿
Hey.
小妞 你走错地方了？
Did you get lost little mouse?
擂台在那
The fight is over there.
还击
Fight!
要不然我俩会被宰
Or they'll kill us both!
真是越来越刺激
And it's about to get exciting.
你的意思是这样？
Ah, you mean this?
夜行者
Nightcrawler!
- 夜行者 - 夜行者
- Nightcrawler! - Nightcrawler!
不好意思
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry!
跟我来
等一下
他们往那边去了
They went that way!
你能变幻
You can transform.
你是她
You're her.
- 那位英雄 - 我谁都不是
- The hero. - I'm nobody.
我不是英雄
I'm not a hero.
我们快离开这里
Let's get out of here.
(波兰 普鲁斯科夫)
晚安 亨利克
Have a good night, Henryk.
晚安 米洛什
You too, Milosz.
嗨 亲爱的
Hi, Honey.
嗨
Hi.
你好？
Good day?
还不错
Better now.
妮娜人呢？
Where's Nina?
在后面 跟她朋友在一块
Out back. With her friends.
别担心
这个够大家喝
∮ 快闭上眼睛 ∮
∮ 进入梦乡 ∮
∮ 做个甜蜜的梦 ∮
这首歌你是在哪学的 老爸？
Where did you learn that song, Papa?
我爸妈教我的
I learned it from my parents.
而他们是跟他们的爸妈学的
And they learned it from their parents.
一代传一代
And them from theirs.
有一天
And one day...
你也会唱给你的子女听
you'll sing it to your children, too.
他们怎么样了？
What happened to them?
你的父母
Your parents.
他们就离我而去了
They were taken from me...
我年纪还小时
when I was a little boy.
但他们永远在这
But they're still here.
我心里
Inside.
也和你
And here.
在一起
With you.
你会离我而去吗？
Is someone going to take you away?
永远不会
Never.
我觉得我们两个太像了
I guess we're more alike than we thought.
他不会听我们的
He won't listen to us.
他总是那样…
He's just... He's being...
史考特
Scott.
让我试试
Let me try.
(泽维尔天赋青少年学校)
这里闻起来很旧
Smells pretty old in here.
究竟是学校还是博物馆
Is this a school or a museum?
还有一阶 最后一阶
One more. And last one.
小心看路
Watch where you're going.
我看不到…
I can't.
你在跟谁说话？
Who are you talking to?
我
Me.
我明明听到你说话
I just heard you in my head.
我有心电感应 我会读心术
I'm telepathic. I read minds.
那离我远点
Well, stay out of mine.
我可不想有个怪女孩在我脑子里钻来钻去
I don't need some weird girl creeping around in there.
别担心 史考特 里面没什么看头
Don't worry, Scott. There's not much to see.
嘿 等等 我没告诉你我的名字
Hey, wait. I didn't tell you my name.
对 你没说
No, you didn't.
亚历克斯·桑莫斯？
Alex Summers?
汉克·麦考伊
Hank McCoy!
哇 那个大蓝毛怪 跑去哪了？
Whoa! What happened to the big, blue, furry you?
我现在控制得很好
I keep him under control now.
这是我弟弟 史考特
This is my brother, Scott.
嗨 史考特 我是汉克·麦考伊 我在这里教书
Hey, Scott. I'm Hank McCoy. I'm one of the teachers here.
教授在哪里？
Where's the professor?
扬弃血腥 忘怀过去
"To break forth bloodily, then the past must be obliterated...
一切从新开始
"and a new start made.
从新开始
"Let us now start fresh...
让我们完全忘掉过去
"without remembrance...
千万不要彷徨犹豫
"rather than live forward and backward at the same time."
作者写这段话是想表达
Now, what on earth do we think that the author meant...
什么样的情绪？
when he wrote all that?
这是你们明天要交的报告
That's going to be your assignment for tomorrow.
好好准备 下课
Top marks, everyone. Class dismissed.
- 亚历克斯 很高兴见到你 - 我也是
- Alex. It's good to see you. - You too.
好久不见 你看起来不错
You look well. It's been a while.
是啊 你看上去也不错
It has. Not too bad yourself.
谢谢
Thank you.
我弟弟 史考特
This is my brother, Scott.
你好 史考特 还迎来天赋学校
Hello, Scott. Welcome to the School for the Gifted.
是吗 我可不觉得这是种天赋
Yeah. It doesn't exactly feel like a gift.
一开始都认为不是
It never does, at first.
了解自己能力的第一步要先知道能力的大小
The first step in understanding one's power is learning the extent of it.
唯有如此 我们才能教你如何控制
Only then can we begin the process of teaching you how to control it.
如果你选择留下 我敢保证
If you do decide to stay, I can promise you...
一旦学成 你返回社会
that by the time you're done here, you'll be able to go back into the world...
就能很稳定快速的融入
and play a stable and productive part in it.
为什么不把把绷带
Why don't you take your bandages off...
解开给我们看看 到底会发生什么
and we can have a look at what we're dealing with here?
亚历克斯 请你扶着他面朝安全之处
Alex, would you line him up? Face him in the right direction, as it were.
水塘对面有个目标
There's a target just across the water.
你睁开眼睛试着瞄准发射
When you open your eyes, try and hit that.
你可以张开眼睛 史考特
You can open your eyes, Scott.
没什么好怕的 十分的…
There's nothing to be afraid of. It's quite...
后退 后退
Look out! Get back!
Get back! Get back!
那棵树是我五岁时我祖父亲手种的
My grandfather planted that tree when he was five years old.
我常常在那荡秋千
I used to swing from the branches of it, myself.
是我最爱的一棵树
I think that was probably my favorite tree.
听这口气是要撵我出去吗？
Does that mean I'm expelled?
正好相反
On the contrary.
你录取了
You're enrolled.
(埃及 开罗)
有卖地毯吗？
Do you sell rugs?
谁让你进来的
You're not allowed in this area.
这块地毯要卖吗？
This rug is for sale?
我说了 这…
I said, this...
早安
哦  万能的神啊
请用你的神力保佑我们 请用你的神力保佑我们
伟大  万能的神
我们是你忠实地信徒
恩·沙巴·奴尔
伟大  万能的神
请用你的神力保佑我们 请用你的威力保佑我们
快看啊
快看
恩·沙巴·奴尔
伟大  万能的神
请用你的神力保佑我们 请用你的威力保佑我们
恩·沙巴·奴尔
伟大  万能的神
请用你的神力保佑我们 请用你的威力保佑我们
我主
怎么回事 ？
恩·沙巴·奴尔
出事了 不妙 不妙
- 快跑 - 快啊 快跑
地震了
Earthquake!
回去睡觉 亲爱的 回去睡觉
Back to bed, please, my darling. Back to bed.
她又做恶梦了
She's doing it again.
大家都回去睡觉
Back to bed, please, everyone.
别看了 回去睡觉
Jesse, back to bed, please.
快点 乖乖 回去睡觉
Come on now. Spit-spot, back to bed.
快点 快点 回去睡觉
Carrie Anne, come on now. Back to bed.
我从未看她这样过
Never seen it like this.
我也是
Nor I.
别让其他孩子来这
Don't let any of the children come this way.
琴
Jean.
Jean!
琴
我预见世界末日
I saw the end of the world.
到处充斥着死亡
I could feel all this death.
不 就只是梦境罢了
It was just a dream.
但一切都那么真实
No, it felt real.
我知道
I know.
你的意念是我见过最强大的.
Your mind is the most powerful I've ever seen.
- 更能说服自身… - 不 这次不一样
- It can convince itself... - No, no... It's not,
不仅仅是读心术或心电感应这么简单
just the mind-reading or the telekinesis...
而是另有其物
it's something else.
有股暗黑力量在我脑中不断增强
Some dark power inside and it's growing. but..
像火焰般
Like a fire.
我还以为自己没事了
I thought I was getting better.
是的 你没事的
You are. You will.
以后也没事 只要耐心点
You just have to be patient.
不 不 你无法体会闭上眼睛时的那种恐惧
No, no. You don't know what it's like to be afraid to shut your eyes.
完全被困在自己的意识里
To be trapped inside your own head.
哦 我觉得我能体会
Oh, I think I do.
不久前我也被脑内的声音困扰过
It wasn't so long ago that I was plagued by voices, myself.
传达着所有的折磨
All their suffering.
和痛苦
All their pain.
以及秘密
Their secrets.
我害怕有一天我会伤害别人
I'm afraid one day I'm going to hurt someone.
躺下
Lie back.
每个人都害怕他们不理解的东西
Everyone fears that which they do not understand.
您要学习去控制自己的能量
You will learn to control your powers.
当你做到了
And when you do...
你就无所畏惧
you'll have nothing to fear.
这次她的恶梦不同于以往
Her nightmares were different this time.
或许这能解释在实验室发现的异象
It could account for something I saw when I was in my lab earlier.
就如同地震释放能量般
There was some kind of tremor. Like an energy surge.
我都有记录
I picked it up on one of my meters.
你是说那是琴造成的
You're saying Jean created it?
不 是别的东西
No. I'm saying something else did.
或许她只是感应到了 我不确定
Maybe she was reacting to it. I don't know.
但是 震波来自地球另一端
But the epicenter was halfway around the world.
- 地球另一端？- 是啊
- Halfway around the world? - Yeah.
所以我希望你能来看看
That's why I was hoping you could take a look.
那就让我们看看能找到什么
Let's see what we can find.
欢迎您教授
Welcome, Professor.
震源位于开罗
Okay, the source came from Cairo.
我替你输入座标
I'll put in the coordinates.
我得离开这里
I gotta get out of here.
向上级报告
Give them a report.
怎么了？有发现什么吗？
What? What is it?
我得汇报这里发生的事
Something happened here. I can tell them it's real.
是她
It's her.
谁？
Who?
- 莫伊拉 - 什么？
- Moira. - What?
莫伊拉·玛塔格？
Moira MacTaggert?
说详细点？
Give me the details.
她看起还是让人惊艳 跟以前一样
She looks amazing. She's barely aged a day.
不 我是说
No. I meant...
她在那干什么？
What is she doing there?
中情局和这事有关？
What does the CIA want with this?
她准备向兰利回报状况
She's going back to Langley to deliver a report.
我要去那里一趟
I'm going to go there...
看看能否帮到她什么忙
see if she knows something about the tremor.
其实是想见莫伊拉一面
And you want to go see Moira.
我是要去看看那里实际情况
I want to go check her out. Check out... the situation.
莫伊拉·玛塔格
Moira MacTaggert.
去见见回忆里的人
It's like a ghost from the past.
你没错 你救了那个人
You did a good thing. You saved that man.
这不是重点
That's not the point.
如果我暴露了 你们都会有危险
If I'm exposed, we're all exposed.
现在必须离开
We have to go.
可这是我们的家啊
This is our home.
也是我们的女儿的家
This is our daughter's home.
我们活着才有家
We are her home.
我们相识的第一个晚上 我就告诉你我是谁
I told you who I was, the first night I met you.
那时我相信你
I trusted you then.
现在你也要相信我
I need you to trust me now.
我们不能再留在这里
We can't stay here anymore.
我去叫妮娜
I'll get Nina.
宝贝？
Sweetheart.
她不在房间里
She's not in her room.
后院也没看到她
And I don't see her out back.
妮娜
Nina?
Nina!
妮娜 妮娜
Nina! Nina!
妮娜
Nina!
Nina.
你没事吧？
Are you alright?
她很好
She's fine.
那么 先放了她
Then let her go!
我们会的
We will.
我们想和你谈谈
We just wanted to have a word
你们都没配戴警徽
You're not wearing your badges.
不需要
No metal.
今天工厂有工人说 他们看到一些事情
Some guys at the factory said they saw something today.
一些不合常理的事情
Something that didn't add up.
请放下武器
Put your weapons away.
你是个好公民 亨利克
You've been a good citizen, Henryk...
好邻居 好工人
A good neighbor... a good worker.
我相信你的为人
I want to believe that's who you are.
他是好人
It is.
但镇上没人真正了解你是谁
But nobody in this town really knows you.
你知道我的
Yes you do.
我是亨利克·古斯基
I am Henryk Gurzsky.
雅各布 我还去你家吃过晚饭
Jakob, I've had dinner in your home...
你一直在骗我们
And you were lying the whole time.
我引狼入室
I brought a killer into my house.
这人是你吗？
Is this you?
你是叫万磁王的这个人吗？
Are you the one they call Magneto?
来抓我吧
Take me in.
拜托
Please...
放了我的女儿
Just let my daughter go.
到你妈妈那边去
Go with your mother.
求你们
Please...
别丢下我
Don't leave me.
- 我不会让他们把你带走 - 妮娜
- I'm not going to let them take you. - Nina.
妮娜
Nina.
求你们了
Please...
怎么回事？
What's going on?
她也是变种人
She's one of them?
快让她住手
Tell her to stop!
她自己控制不了
She can't control it!
她吓坏了
She's scared of you!
我不会让他们带你走 我不会让他们带你走
I'm not going to let them take you!
快让她住手
Make her stop!
妮娜
Nina! Nina!
Nina.
妮娜 妮娜 不要
Nina, Nina, no...
不要啊 求你 求你
No, please. Please!
求你了
Please.
拜托
别这样对我的孩子
Not my babies.
不要这样对我的孩子
这就是你们想要的吗？
Is this what you want from me?
我命该如此吗？
Is this what I am?
妈的 有小偷 抓小偷
抓住她 抓小偷
你知道当小偷的下场吗？
You know what we do to thieves.
选一只手
Pick a hand.
够了
Enough.
你跟她是一伙的
If you're with her, I suggest you walk away.
我建议你
While you still can.
最好滚开
Walk away
是谁统治这个世界？
Who rules this world?
你说的哪国的话？
What language is that?
丑八怪 你到底想干嘛？
Clown-face. What's the deal?
滚开
Beat it!
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你感受不到 是吗？
You can't feel it, can you?
现在 你感受到了吧
Now you feel it.
这么说 这些年你真没见过她？
So you really haven't seen her in all these years?
也没找过她？甚至没想过？
You never looked her up? Not even in Cerebro?
亚历克斯 你把我当成变态狂吗？
Alex! What do you take me for, some kind of pervert?
没错 我偷看过她一次 是两次
Yes, I looked her up once. Twice.
可就一下下 懂吗？
But not in a long time, all right?
你怎么做到的？不会舍不得吗？
How did you leave things? Any hard feelings?
当然会
Not likely.
但人总要喘口气吧
Everybody take a break.
我抹去了她对我们之间所有的记忆
I wiped her mind of all memories of us.
海滩 古巴
The beach, Cuba...
所有的事情
that whole time.
那可是很久以前的事了 亚历克斯
It was so long ago, Alex.
当时人们还不知道有变种人存在
Before the world knew about mutants.
所以我觉得那样对她才是最好的
I felt it was the best thing for her.
那你呢？
And for you?
对我来说好坏都不重要
Didn't really matter what was best for me.
莫伊拉·玛塔格 你好
Moira...MacTaggert, hello!
请允许我自我介绍
Allow me to introduce myself.
- 我是… - 查尔斯·泽维尔
- I'm Professor... - Charles Xavier.
- 我当然知道你是谁 - 你知道？
- I know exactly who you are. - You do?
当然知道
Of course I do.
您所有论文我都拜读过
I have read all of your papers.
很高兴终于见到你本人
It's a pleasure to finally meet you.
莫伊拉·玛塔格
Moira MacTaggert.
- 亚历克斯·桑莫斯 - 请坐
- Alex Summers. - Have a seat.
那个 把它放地上就好
Just throw that on the floor.
再次见到你太好了
It's wonderful to see you again.
我是说初次见面很荣幸
To meet you again, for the first time.
你有个儿子？
You've got a son?
是啊
Yes.
他有丈夫 还是？
Does he have a husband?
你有丈夫吗？
Do you have a husband?
我之前有过
I had a husband...
可是 这工作很难让我按时回家做饭
but it's hard to do this job and make it home in time for dinner.
说得太对
Good, good.
牺牲在所难免 对吧？
We all make choices, right?
是的 确实是
Yes, we do.
- 教授 - 是的？
- Professor. - Yes?
是
Yes.
我是 我们来这希望 你能
I was, we were hoping that you would...
告诉我们昨天在埃及发生的事情
tell us about what happened yesterday in Egypt.
恐怕这是机密
I'm afraid that's classified information.
恕我无礼 不过
And, I don't mean to be rude, but...
你们是怎么进来的？
how did you get in here?
我有第5级权限
I have level-five clearance.
自从73年人类发现了变种人
Ever since the world found out about mutants in '73...
就有很多狂热分子视他们为
there have been cults who see them as some kind of...
上帝重现的征兆
Second Coming or sign of God.
我追踪他们中的一个
I was tracking one of them.
他自称恩·沙巴·奴尔
They call themselves Ashir En Sabah Nur...
这名字自古即有且为世界第一
named after an ancient being they believe to be the world's first.
世界第一是指什么呢？
The world's first what?
世界上第一个变种人
The world's first mutant.
我以为变种人是本世纪的产物
I thought mutants didn't evolve until this century.
理论上来说是 但有些人相信
That's the common theory, yes, but these guys believe...
变种人始祖出现在数万年前
that the first mutant was born tens of thousands of years ago.
更相信他会复活
And they believe he will rise again.
因此寻遍世界上所有古迹遗址
They've been searching ancient sites all around the world for clues.
这些象形文字
These hieroglyphs...
记载了某种超能力 无人能驾驭的神秘力量
describe a specific set of powers greater than any man could possess.
他们认为他会复活？
They think he lived all that time?
不全然是 他们相信他有某种能力
Yes and no. They believe he had the ability...
可以把他的意识移转到另外一个躯体上
to transfer his consciousness from body to body.
每当他濒临死亡
And whenever he was close to death...
他会选择一个新的躯体
he would just take on a new body.
其中有变种人
Some of these may have been the bodies of mutants...
他就吸取他们的力量
enabling him to take their powers...
累积不同的天赋
amassing various abilities over the years.
- 成为一个全能的变种人 - 完全正确
- An all-powerful mutant. - Exactly.
无论他出现在何处 身边总是会有4个忠仆 门徒
And wherever this being was he always had four principle followers. Disciples.
他会赋予他们力量作为他的守护者
Protectors he would imbue with powers.
像圣经里的
Like the Four Horsemen...
天启四骑士
of the Apocalypse.
他抄袭圣经
He got that one from the Bible.
又或者圣经出自他手
Or the Bible got it from him.
无论他统治哪里
And wherever he ruled...
最终 都以灾难收场
eventually, it would end in disaster. Cataclysm.
也许这就是圣经中所谓的…
Some kind of...
天启
Apocalypse
世界末日
The end of the world.
我不得不说 阿波罗
I must say, Apollo...
你扮成人类的还真有模有样
the way you ape human behavior is remarkable.
小孩子都出去
快点 快点
我是阿波罗
I am Apollo.
我在这镇上从没有见其他变种人
I've never seen another mutant in this town.
你会说埃及话？
You speak Egyptian?
还是阿拉伯语？
Arabic?
英语呢？
English?
伟大的战士
Great fighter.
她是我的英雄
She's my hero.
我想像她一样
I want to be like her.
这里有些吃的 份量不多
There's some food here. Not much.
我不相信
I don't believe it.
你爱我
You love me.
爱你？
Love you?
你还当真啊
Illogical.
我不是会轻易爱上人的牧羊女
I'm not some simple shepherdess you can awe.
让我爱你 那我宁愿爱上一个变种的细菌
Why, I could no more love you than I could love a new species of bacteria.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
学习
Learning.
街道上满是反对苏联入侵阿富汗
In the streets, there is outrage against the Soviet invasion of Afghanistan...
像我们这样愤怒的兄弟
...in a brotherhood of our kind.
一些示威游行
Several demonstrations.
波士顿也有游行 布鲁斯莫顿有故事
One of them was held in Boston, and Bruce Morton has the story.
由于核武器强大威吓 美国不会主动开启战端…
Since the advent of nuclear weapons, the United States does not start fights.
武器
Weapons.
前所未见如此强大的力量
Never before has man possessed so much power.
导致苏联和美国成为超级大国
Soviet Union and United States being superpowers...
超级大国
Superpowers.
人类这么弱还能统治地球
The weak have taken the earth.
还曾背叛过我
For this, I was betrayed.
这些伪神
False gods.
领袖
Idols.
都将不复存在
No more.
我已回归
I have returned.
新的未来
A new tomorrow...
始于今日
that starts today.
你从哪里来的？
Where did you come from?
在人类尚未迷失方向的时候
A time before man lost his way.
那么欢迎来到80年代
Welcome to the '80s.
这个世界需要…
This world needs to be...
净化
Cleansed.
什么？
What?
拯救
Saved.
乱杀无辜拯救不了这个世界
You can't save the world just going around killing people.
我们有法律来规范人的行为
There's laws, systems in place for that kind of thing.
我的孩子
My child...
你为什么要束缚自己的天赋？
why do you enslave yourself?
你想干嘛？
What are you doing?
让你变得更强
Making you stronger.
我的女神
My goddess.
没错
Yes.
你说的对
You were right.
时代已经不同
The time is past.
再也不需要神了
There is no room for gods.
为什么不让我和你一起去
Why can't I go with you?
我说了 我是独行侠
I told you, I work alone.
在那等着
Wait there.
看到你的脸是件好事
Always good to see your face.
即使那不是你的
Even if it's not yours.
给我一份通行证
Papers and passage for one.
没问题 那这位男士是要去哪？
Where's the gentleman going, if I may ask?
不知道 不关我事
Don't know, don't care.
我只是救了他 其他和我无关
I just save his life. What he does with it is up to him.
雇佣兵 魔形女
Mystique, the mercenary.
别那么叫我
Don't call me that.
不管你伪装成任何人
No matter how much you pretend to be someone else...
我卡列班都能认出你来
Caliban knows who you are.
关于变种人的所有讯息
If there's anything worth knowing about mutants...
卡利班都知道
Caliban knows it.
魔形女
Mystique.
想知道再这么鸡鸡歪歪的下场吗
Why don't you ask your psychics what'll happen to you if you keep pushing me?
会有什下场？
What'll happen?
灵蝶吃醋了
Psylocke gets a little jealous.
因为卡列班喜欢你
But Caliban likes you.
卡利班喜欢的是钱
Caliban likes money.
卡列班真的很喜欢你
Caliban likes you so much...
所以要免费送你一件消息
he wants to give you free information...
是关于你的一位老友
about an old friend...
如果你们还是
from back when you had friends.
你还记得
Do you remember...
艾瑞克·兰谢尔吗？
Erik Lehnsherr?
我的人看到他在波兰的照片
My girls got a flash of him in Poland.
他身旁有一堆尸体
He left quite a few dead bodies in his wake...
其中包括他的妻子和女儿
including his wife and daughter.
新闻应该很快就发布了 但是卡列班愿意先告诉你
Should be in the news soon enough but Caliban gives you a little head start.
- 你能有多快？- 多快？
- How fast are you? - How fast?
你传输的最大范围
How far can you cover?
我能看到 或者曾经去过的地方
As far as I can see or if I've been there before.
跟我来 爬行者
Come with me, Crawler.
应该叫我夜行者
Actually, it's Nightcrawler.
其实我本名叫
And my real name is...
库尔特·华格纳
Kurt Wagner.
镜片是由红色的石英做的
The lenses are made of some ruby quartz I had lying around.
应该能折射你发射的光束
They should be able to refract your optic beams...
并保存在向量场内
and keep them contained within their own vector fields.
戴上试试
Try them on.
好了 继续
Okay. Go ahead.
等等 抱歉 不是这边
Wait, sorry, no.
好的
Okay.
- 现在？- 是啊 做得不错
- Now? - Yeah, you're good.
好吧
All right.
哇
Whoa.
我可以看到了
I can see.
谢谢
Thank you.
教授 谢谢 你真是个天才
Professor, thank you. You're a genius.
不
No.
我还不是教授 我希望
I'm not a professor. I wish...
那是谁？
Who's that?
我想你们两个已经见过了 她是琴·葛蕾
I believe you two met. That's Jean Grey.
你刚到这里时碰到过她
You bumped into her when you arrived.
- 等一下 这是她？- 是啊
- Wait, that's her? - Yeah.
嘿
Hey.
你能看到了
You can see.
是啊 这里没有我想像的那么糟
Yeah. It's not as bad as I thought here.
怪物
Freak.
- 应该有人警告这个新来的家伙 - 对 有人应该告诉他
- Someone should warn the new kid. - Yeah. Someone should tell him.
他们还是挺怕我的
They're still scared of me.
嘿 我现在有神奇的眼镜啦
Hey, I have special glasses now.
他们不是怕你
They're not scared of you.
他们害怕的是我
They're scared of me.
你不是唯一不能完全控制能力的人
You're not the only one who can't fully control your powers.
等等 这么说
Wait, so...
昨晚的地震
last night, when the house shook...
是你搞的吗？
that was you?
很抱歉吓到你 所以你不是这所学校最大的怪人
Sorry to break it to you, but you're not the biggest freak in the school.
好吧 叫你第一名
Well, that's a first.
瑞雯
Raven.
哇
Wow.
我 你
I... You're...
不是蓝色？
Not blue?
我跟你一样
Looks like you and I have that in common, now.
不 不 我的意思是 你
No, no, I meant... you
你回来了
you're back.
没想到能在这见到你
Never thought I'd see you here again.
是啊 我也是
Yeah, me neither.
我是蓝人
I'm blue.
我叫库尔特
I'm Kurt.
啊对了
Oh, right.
库尔特·华格纳
Kurt Wagner.
欢迎
Welcome.
我们打烊了
We're closed.
我就说怎么冷飕飕的
I knew I felt a chill in the air.
你是怎么进来的？
How did you get in here?
就这么进来的
We let ourselves in.
我们来找变种人
We are looking for mutants.
你知道怎么能找到他们 所以我们来找你
Since you know where to find them, we came here.
卡列班不认识你
Caliban doesn't know you.
我们在找最强的变种人
We're looking for the strongest.
没事吧？
Everything all right?
我没事 灵蝶
I'm fine, Psylocke.
你们带了多少钱？
How much money do you have?
没有
None.
卡列班说过…
Like Caliban said...
我们打烊了 懂吗？
we are closed. Yeah?
我需要你的帮忙 孩子
I need your help, my child.
你看上去不像卡利班他爸
You don't look like Caliban's father.
除了没毛这点
Maybe a little bit up here.
你们都是我的子孙
You are all my children...
你们都迷失了方向 因为你们跟错了领路者
and you're lost, because you follow blind leaders.
那些愚蠢的伪神
These false gods...
和脆弱的体制
systems of the weak.
我不允许他们继续毁灭我的世界…
They've ruined my world...
绝不
No more.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
我要你
I want you...
感受到你真正的实力
to feel the full reach of your power.
目前你只发挥了很小一部分
You've only had a taste of your true strength.
不像那些试图控制你的人
Unlike others who seek to control you...
我要完全释放你
I want to set you free.
我想我知道你要找的人是谁了
I know the kind of mutants you're looking for.
我能帮你找到他们
And I know where to find them.
这是我第一次来美国
It's my first time in America.
我很想见识一下你们的文化
I'm very excited to see your culture.
在这你可看不到
Well, you're not gonna see it here.
这里只有英国人留下的东西
The only thing American about this place is that it used to be British.
这是史考特
This is Scott.
他也是新来的
He's new here, too.
而且我越狱计划已备妥了
And I'm already up for a prison break.
我说蓝精灵要不要一起出去兜风？
What do we say, we take this blue guy on a little field trip?
我知道这附近有座大卖场
I'm sure there's a mall around here, somewhere.
大卖场是什么？
What's a mall?
基于民族自尊心 更应该带他见识一下
All right, now this is a matter of national pride. Civic duty.
史考特
Scott.
怎么了？你被关在这里太久了
What? You've been cooped up here for a long time...
反正教授不在家
and the Professor's not even home.
我挺想去大卖场看看
I'd like to go to the mall.
尝试一下
Try it.
很好
All right.
教授的车放哪了？
Where does he keep his cars?
(皮斯马戏团)
听不懂吗 我说了"滚开"？
Or should I say "piss off"?
就是这家伙
This is the guy?
他曾经是
He used to be.
我不知道他的翅膀变得…
I didn't know his wings were...
我们走吧
Let's get out of here.
他的能力不比从前了
His fighting days are done.
不 你错了
No, they're not.
你们到底想干什么？
What the hell is this?
我想送你一样东西
I want to give you something.
你给不了任何我想要的东西
There's nothing you can give me that I want.
他可以
Yes, there is.
很好 乖宝宝
Yes, my son.
不错
Yes.
起来 我的天使
Rise, my angel.
飞啊
Rise.
超音速 防爆 具隐形功能
Hypersonic, blast resistant, stealth technology.
太惊人了
That's impressive.
你怎么把它从这里弄出去？
How are you ever gonna get it out of here?
这不用担心
Well, that's okay.
篮球场上方是可移动式屋顶
I built a retractable roof into the basketball court.
汉克 你在这里造了一架战斗机
Hank, you're building a warplane down here.
从华盛顿发生事故之后 我认为我们应该重新
After what happened in Washington, I thought we were going to come back...
启动X战警计划 就像我们之前设想的…
and start the X-Men, like we all used to talk about.
但
But...
查尔斯要的是学生而不是战士
Charles wants students, not soldiers.
他相信人类
And he thinks the best of people.
且存有幻想
He has hope.
那你呢？
And you?
我认为我们应该抱持希望
You know, I think we should hope for the best.
同时要做最坏的打算
And prepare for the worst.
这个世界需要X战警
I think the world needs the X-Men.
既然现在你回来了 或许你能帮我说服他
And maybe now that you're back, you could help me convince him.
- 让我们… - 汉克 我回来是为了艾瑞克
- We could start it together. - Hank, I'm here about Erik.
对 艾瑞克
Right. Erik.
嗯 当然了
Yeah. Of course.
- 当然 - 我想他可能遇到了麻烦
- Of course. - I think he might be in some kind of trouble.
大麻烦
Real trouble.
他哪次不是这样？
Isn't he always?
你们昨天有人把看到自以为是的事情
Some of you spoke to the police...
向警察告密
about what you believe you witnessed here yesterday.
你们想知道我的能力吗？
You want to know my powers...
想知道我是谁？
know who I am...
看看我能做些什么？
see what I can do?
我会让你们知道
I'll show you.
想一想你们生命中最爱的人
Think of the person you love most in your life.
妻子
Your wife.
母亲
Mother.
和女儿
Daughter.
他们很快就会尝到失去至爱的滋味
Now that person will know what it is to lose someone they love.
在悲痛中度过一生
And live with that pain.
永远
Forever.
亨利克 求你了
Henryk, please.
不要这样做
Don't do this.
我的名字不叫亨利克
My name isn't Henryk.
我叫万磁王
My name is Magneto.
你们他妈的谁啊？
Who the fuck are you?
退后
Stay back.
不管你是谁
Whoever you are...
别想试着阻止我杀了这些人
don't try to stop me from killing these men.
我在这里不是为了他们
I'm not here for them.
我是为你而来
I'm here for you.
来看看
Come and see.
(奥斯威辛集中营)
你的天赋由此而生
This is where your power was born.
同时也是你的同胞被屠杀的地方
And this is where your people were slaughtered.
你不应该带我来这里
You shouldn't have brought me here.
为什么？
Why?
你害怕到这里来？
Are you afraid to be here?
你摆脱不了 艾瑞克
You can't escape it, Erik.
你是谁？
Who are you?
耶和华 神 太阳神
Elohim, Shen, Ra.
我在无数次轮回中有太多的称呼
I've been called many names over many lifetimes.
我在死亡中诞生
I am born of death.
我将点燃唤醒人类的火焰
I was there to spark and fan the flame of man's awakening.
倾覆文明的车轮
To spin the wheel of civilization.
播种新的种子
And when the forest would grow rank...
让世界走向正轨…
and needed clearing for new growth...
我正履行使命点燃这把火
I was there to set it ablaze.
你去哪了？
Where were you...
当我的父母在这被屠杀的时候？
when my father and mother were slaughtered in this place?
沉睡
Asleep.
被困在黑暗中
Trapped in darkness.
当时我无法到此 孩子
I was not there for you, my son.
可现在有我
But I am here now.
我比你更了解你的能力有多强大
You don't know your own strength, but I do.
用心灵感受
Reach down.
蕴藏在地下的金属
Feel the metal in the ground.
感受地心深处的黑暗
Reach as deep as you can.
你会发现你拥有足以颠覆世界的力量
You'll find you have the power to move the very Earth itself.
人类创建的一切都会崩塌
Everything they've built will fall!
而我们将在这灰烬之上
And from the ashes of their world...
缔造一个更好的世界
we'll build a better one!
昨晚波兰中部的一个小镇 发现兰谢尔踪迹
Lehnsherr was identified yesterday, in this small town in central Poland.
各国领导人呼吁国人保持冷静
Leaders from all communities are urging their citizens to remain calm.
当地在警察和军队 正在严密搜索在逃犯万磁王
As police and armed forces are mobilizing to find Lehnsherr...
以防止其发起另一波攻击
...before he can strike again.
如果任何人有兰谢尔
If anyone has information about Lehnsherr...
更准确说应是万磁王的消息
or as he is also known, Magneto...
请立即联系您当地警方
contact your local authorities immediately...
并请保持警惕
and proceed with caution...
- 因为他是极度危险的人物 - 皮特
- as he is considered extremely... - Peter.
怎么了？
What's up?
看看你在干嘛
Just checking on you.
我很好 玩小精灵
I'm good. Playing Pac-Man.
你真的不过来看这个？
You sure you weren't watching this?
人们都在庆祝与变种人和平共处10周年之际
This news comes at a time when the world is celebrating 10 years of peace...
一则惊人消息传来
between mutants and mankind.
你是不是想去找他？
You're going after him, aren't you?
你不是让我多出去走走吗？
You wanted me to get out of the house more, right?
我拦不住你 也没人能
I can't stop you. Nobody can.
但相信我 这不会有好结果
But trust me, this won't end well.
只要跟他扯上关系
Nothing does with him.
我才不怕他
I'm not afraid of him.
最好是
You should be.
(泽维尔天才青少年学校 查尔斯·泽维尔教授)
我在文章里读到过这个地方
I've read so much about this place.
实际到了这里 似乎有些熟悉的…
But being here, it actually seems kind of...
感觉
familiar.
真诡异
Strange.
完全同意
Quite.
下车吧？
Shall we?
(正在放映《星球大战：绝地归来》)
还是"帝国大反击"最经典
I'm just saying, Empire is still the best.
不仅剧情复杂 人物描写也很丰满
It's the most complex, the most sophisticated...
结局又不太悲惨
wasn't afraid to have a dark ending.
不过拜托 如果没有第一部
Yeah, but come on. If it wasn't for the first one...
就不会有后面的续集
you wouldn't have any of the rest of the movies.
至少我们一致同意第三部最烂
Well, at least we can all agree, the third one's always the worst.
汉克 你在吗？
Hank. Are you in here?
我想让你见见…
I'd like you to meet...
莫伊拉
Moira.
瑞雯？
Raven.
抱歉 我们认识吗？
I'm sorry, have we met?
汉克 亚历克斯 玛塔格探员 能让我们单独谈两句吗？
Hank, Alex, Agent MacTaggert, would you give us just one moment, please?
当然
Of course.
查尔斯 她为什么没认出我？她见过我这种样子
Charles, why didn't she recognize me? She knew me in this form.
当年在古巴海滩 你离开之后
Well, after you left me on the beach in Cuba...
我消除了她的那段记忆 请坐
I took her memories of that time. Have a seat.
幸运的女孩
Lucky girl.
很高兴见到你 瑞雯
It's good to see you, Raven.
- 欢迎回家 - 这不是我的家
- Welcome home. - This isn't my home.
至少曾经是
It was once.
不 这是你家 我只是住过而已
No, it was your home. I just lived here.
现在我几乎都认不出来了
And I barely even recognize it now.
你知道到我对这地方的憧憬
You know, I have plans for this place.
我是想把它变成真正的校园
I mean to turn it into a real campus.
一所大学
A university.
不仅是为变种人 普通人也能加入
Not just for mutants, either, for humans too.
一起生活 一起工作
Living and working...
一起成长
growing together.
你知道 我以前也很相信这些
You know, I really believed that once.
华盛顿事件后我以为我们能改变他们
I really believed we could change them after DC.
没有吗
We did.
不 查尔斯 他们仍然害怕及憎恶我们
No, Charles. They still hate and fear us.
只是表面很难看出来 他们更小心了
It's just harder to see because they're more polite about it.
我受够了这种谎言
I got sick of living that lie.
所以你才不想让别看到你原本的样貌
That's why you're not in your natural blue form.
我不想用一个不存在的世界的样貌出现
I'm not gonna be the face of a world that doesn't exist.
情况越来越好 世界也变得更好
Things are better. The world is better.
也许在威彻斯特是这样
Maybe in Westchester.
可是在外面 变种人仍在逃亡
Out there, mutants are still running...
躲避 生活在恐惧中
hiding, living in fear.
即使没有战争 并不代表世界是和平的
Just because there's not a war, doesn't mean there's peace.
真要教孩子有用的东西
You want to teach your kids something, teach them that.
就该教他们如何战斗
Teach them to fight.
否则他们一辈子都只能躲在这理
Otherwise they might as well live in this house for the rest of their lives.
你说话的样子 跟当年的艾瑞克一样
You still sound just like him.You sound just like Erik.
我这次回来 也是因为他
That's why I'm here.
他复出了
He's resurfaced.
他的妻子和女儿都死了
He had a wife and a child. They were killed.
为报仇他杀了几个警察
Along with a handful of policemen.
全世界在找他
The whole world will be looking for him.
在被找到之前 请你先帮我找到他
But you can help me find him before they do.
莫伊拉 请你务必保守这个秘密
Moira, I'm going to have to ask you to keep this a secret.
我都不知道这是个什么… 东西
I don't even know what this is.
这是超脑
It's Cerebro.
进化版
The new model.
没错 采用颜色
I based the color on...
无所谓
It doesn't matter.
那些是什么？
What are those?
这些全是世界上的人类
Those are all the humans of the world.
而这些…
And these...
是变种人
are all the mutants.
我连接感应到他们每个人
I'm connected to all of their minds.
中情局做梦都会想有这个
The CIA would kill for this.
绝对会
I know they would.
你在哪里 艾瑞克？
Where are you, Erik?
查尔斯？
Charles?
你好 老朋友
Hello, old friend.
抱歉 我很遗憾
I'm sorry. I am so sorry!
我感受到你的痛苦
I feel your pain.
和你的遭遇
And your loss.
你以为 因为你能感应到我的想法
You think because you can see into my head...
你就懂那种感受吗？
you know how it feels?
你找错了地方了 查尔斯
You're looking in the wrong place, Charles.
事情不该是这样的 这是个可怕的错误
What happened to them, it was terribly wrong.
回来吧 艾瑞克
But come back to us.
让我来帮你
I can help you.
帮我？
Help me?
想想你的妻子和女儿
Think of your wife, think of your daughter.
他们想要的是什么？
What would they have wanted?
他们只是想活着而已
They would have wanted to live.
我试过你的方法 查尔斯
I tried your way, Charles.
我试着像他们一样
I tried to be like them.
简单地活着
Live like them.
但结局总是一样
But it always ends the same way.
他们夺走了我的一切
They took everything away from me.
现在…
Now...
轮到我们去夺取他们的
we'll take everything from them.
汉克
Hank...
他不是一个人
he's not alone.
太不可思议
Extraordinary.
你看到了什么？
What do you see?
我要的答案
The answer.
查尔斯 等等
Hey, Charles, wait.
哦 我的天啊
Oh, my God.
谢谢你让我进入你的意识
Thank you for letting me in.
查尔斯 快出来
Charles, get out!
查尔斯？
Charles,
我从未感受过如此强大的力量
I've never felt power like this before.
查尔斯
Charles...
查尔斯 快出来
Charles, get out of there.
这是怎么了 发生什么事了？
What's going on? What's happening?
我认为…
I think...
有人侵入了超脑
Someone's taken over Cerebro.
- 而且控制了它 - 为了什么？
- They've taken control of it. - To do what?
连接查尔斯
To connect.
一如既往
Always the same.
眼前这一切
And now, all this.
不再需要石块
No more stones.
不再需要长矛
No more spears.
不再需要抛石器
No more slings.
不再需要长剑
No more swords.
不再需要武器
No more weapons!
也不再需要任何制度
No more systems!
全部不再需要
No more!
更不需要超级大国
No more superpowers.
查尔斯
Charles!
汉克
Hank!
这到底是怎么回事？
What the hell is going on?
谁动了钥匙？
Who's turning the keys?
在我们手里啊
The men are.
谁下令发射的？
Who green-lit the launch?
汉克 想想办法
Hank, do something!
它关不掉
It won't shut down!
我们与三叉戟和北极星潜艇失去了联系
We've lost contact with all Trident and Polaris subs.
空军也回报了同样的状况
The Air Force is reporting the same thing.
他们太依赖 武器
So much faith in their tools...
和装备
and their machines.
俄罗斯 中国
Russia, China...
英国 以色列 印度
England, Israel, India.
都发射了核弹
Everybody's got nukes in the air.
目标为何？
What's the target?
要打哪里？
Where are they going?
向上 直线上升
Up, straight up.
亚历克斯
Alex...
- 什么？- 毁了它
- What? - Destroy it!
摧毁这一切 摧毁超脑
Destroy everything. Destroy Cerebro!
彻底摧毁
Wreak havoc!
你可以从通天塔发射弓弩
You can fire your arrows from the Tower of Babel...
但你永远无法挑战上帝
but you can never strike God!
查尔斯 查尔斯 你没事吧？
Charles, Charles, are you okay?
艾瑞克
Erik.
查尔斯
Charles!
亚历克斯
Alex!
嘿
Hey!
嘿 混蛋
Hey, asshole!
一切即将揭晓 孩子们
All will be revealed, my child.
停下
Stop!
不
No!
哇
Wow!
你从哪里？
Where did you...
我一直在找教授 我以为他住在这里
I was looking for the Professor. I thought he lived here.
他们把他带走了
They took him.
就是她 是她
She's the one. It's her.
你确定？
Are you sure?
她会帮助我们吗？
Is she gonna help us?
他们尊重你
They look up to you.
现在
Right now...
他们需要你
they need you.
这不是他们需要的
That's not what they need.
这太棒了吧
That's awesome!
发生了什么？亚历克斯在哪？
What happened? Where's Alex?
我哥哥在哪了？
Where's my brother?
我很确定我救了所有人
Pretty sure I got everybody.
亚历克斯在最接近爆炸的地方
Alex was closest to the blast.
亚历克斯
Alex...
我们一步到位
We're one click out.
好吧 孩子们 就这样了
All right, boys. This is it.
请保持冷静
医疗救援已在途中
Medical assistance is on the way.
请保持冷静
Please remain calm.
医疗救援已在途中
Medical assistance is on the way.
请保持冷静
Please remain calm.
医疗救援已在途中
Medical assistance is on the way.
请保持冷静
Please remain calm.
医疗救援已在途中
Medical assistance is on the way.
嘿 我是莫伊拉·玛塔格
Hey! Moira MacTaggert!
CIA 谢天谢地你们来啦
CIA! Thank God you're here!
等等
Wait!
开火
Fire!
我要她
I want her.
他
Him.
- 和她 - 是的先生
- And her. - Yes, sir.
别管这些孩子
Leave the kids.
- 我们干什么？- 安静
- What do we do? - Keep quiet.
X射线7号 我在周围做最后一次检查
X-Ray 7, I'm doing a final sweep of the ground.
好吧 你 安全吗？
Let's get them on the bird!
安全
Clear!
收拾起来 我们走吧
快 行动
谢谢你 琴 我们一定要帮助他们
Thanks, Jean. We gotta help them.
- 库尔特 你能带我们进入那个东西里吗？- 你想进入那里？
- Kurt, can you get us in that thing? - You want to get in there?
如果那些士兵看见我们怎么办？
What if the soldiers see us?
不要担心 他们不会看到我们 相信我
Don't worry, they won't see us. Trust me.
等一下
Hold on.
库尔特 带我们都离开这里
Kurt, get us all out of here!
我不能
I can't!
他们关了门以后 产生了某种电场
When they closed the doors, there's some kind of electrical field.
它就像柏林围墙一样
It's like Berlin all over.
琴 控制飞行员 不要让他们起飞
Jean, get in the pilots' heads. Don't let them take off.
我做不到 我无法操控飞行员 我不能操控任何人
I can't. I can't reach the pilots. I can't reach anyone.
我们也收到来自欧洲和亚洲的消息
We're also getting reports out of Europe and Asia.
不仅是美国有此情事
This was not just a U.S. phenomenon.
似乎世界各地都使用核武
It seems the entire world has been disarmed of nuclear weapons.
五角大厦已经证实 大多数核弹来自俄罗斯
The Pentagon has confirmed multiple launches...
还有英国 以色列和中国
from Russia, as well as the UK, Israel and China.
- 看 - 那上面
- Look! - Look up there!
到目前为止 白宫尚未发表任何声明
So far, there has been no response from the White House.
目击证人来自世界各地
Eyewitness reports have been pouring in from affiliates across the globe.
当局无法分辨属于和平还是战争行为
Authorities are not sure if it was an act of peace or an act of war.
亲爱的天父
Our dear Father...
请引领我们走向光明
hold me in the light of God.
出事的应该是我
It should have been me.
他这一生还有很多大事
He was the one that was gonna do something with his life.
要靠他完成
He was always the one.
这不全然是他的想法
That's not how he felt.
他觉得你也是能成就大事的人
He felt you were the one that was gonna do something special with your life.
你能让影响这世界
That you were gonna make a difference in the world.
甚至改变它
Maybe even change it.
你怎么知道他的想法？
How do you know what he felt?
我知道所有人的想法
I know what everybody feels.
引领我们走向光明
Hold me in the light of God.
免我于危难
Protect me from danger.
以您的示谕拯救我
Save me by Your command.
请聆听我的祷告
Listen to my prayer.
保佑我
And keep me safe.
你限制了我的能力我
You're blocking me.
怎么回事？
How?
我能阻挡你侵入他们的意识
I can shield their minds from your power.
这是我千百年来获得的众多天赋之一
It's one of the many gifts I've acquired throughout the millennia.
但要洞悉他人的意识
But to see inside a mind...
及控制它
to control it...
那是你的天赋
that's your gift.
你领略到了 不是吗？
You saw it, didn't you?
即将发生壮观景象
The glory of what's to come.
你要参与这场杀戮 毁灭世界吗？
You're going to take part in all this killing and destruction?
这我早就知道
It's all I've ever known.
不 你不知道
No, it isn't.
你只是忘了
You've just forgotten.
不 查尔斯 我都记得
No, Charles, I remember.
你的方式是行不通的
Your way doesn't work.
我给他一个更好的选择 更好的世界
I've shown him a better way.A better world.
你就是在利用他的愤怒和痛苦 仅此而已
No, you've just tapped into his rage and pain. That's all you've done.
我们相遇那一刻起我就告诉过你
I told you from the moment I met you, there is more to you, Erik.
你身上还有很多美好的事物
There is good in you, too.
不论你在我身上看到了什么 查尔斯
Whatever it is you think you saw in me, Charles...
我已将它和我的家人
I buried it...
一同埋葬了
with my family.
- 怎么了？- 怎么回事？
- What? - What?
你怎么变成这样？
What's wrong with you?
我们也会这样吗？
Is that going to happen to all of us?
不会 我忘了带药出来
No, I just... left my meds in the house.
发生什么事？我们在哪里？
What happened? Where are we?
嘿
Hey!
你好 魔形女
Hello, Mystique.
史崔克少校
Major Stryker.
是史崔克上校
Colonel Stryker.
如果我是你 我不会离墙太近
I wouldn't get too close to the wall, if I were you.
那会让你们有些不适…
It may create some discomfort.
我是莫伊拉·玛塔格 CIA高级官员
I'm Moira MacTaggert. I'm a senior officer at the CIA.
我知道你是谁 玛塔格探员
I know who you are, Agent MacTaggert.
你无权把我关在这…
You cannot keep me here, in this...
我当然有权
Actually, I can.
通灵事件销毁了所有的核弹
A psychic event just destroyed every nuke from here to Moscow.
我们在案发地点找到了你们
That event emanated from exactly where we found you.
那座世上最强大的心灵研究园地
At the home of the world's most powerful psychic.
所以现在请你诉我查尔斯·泽维尔人在何方？
So, you are going to tell me, where is Charles Xavier?
你现在该担心的不是查尔斯
It's not him you should be worried about.
还有一个人有更强大力量
There's someone else. Someone more powerful.
如果你放了我们 我们还能帮你
If you let us out of here, we can help you.
你真以为我会相信你说的吗？
Do you really expect me to believe that?
你能伪装成任何人 可我知道你是谁
You can put on any face that you want, but I know who you are.
还有你的能耐
What you are.
嘿 莫伊拉
Hey, Moira.
你说还有人比查尔斯更厉害？
What did you mean when you said someone more powerful than Charles?
等他做完这个 我们就出发
Once they finish these, we'll go from there.
怎么还没搞定？
What's taking so long?
我进不去
I can't get in.
里面好像也有磁场
They have a field around it, like the helicopter.
得想办法切断电源
There's gotta be a way to cut the power.
查尔斯
Charles...
你要把我的话传送给世上所有人
you will send a message...to every living mind.
你要告诉他们 这地球将变成废墟
You will tell them that this earth will be laid waste.
这是我 恩·沙巴·奴尔对类人的惩罚
That it is I, En Sabah Nur...who will wreak this upon them.
现在
Now...
传递我的讯息
deliver my message.
就算我愿意
Even if I wanted to...
没有超脑我无法同时连接所有人的脑
I couldn't reach that many people. I don't have Cerebro.
你不需要机器… 来增强你的能力
You don't need a machine to amplify your powers.
你有我
You have me.
各位 我们可以靠这个出去
Guys, that could be our way out of here.
你认识他？万磁王
You know him? Magneto?
曾经
I used to.
现在我不确定
Not so sure anymore.
他是什么样的人？
What was he like?
他是不是像人们说的那样 他是
Was he like they say he was? Was he...
是个坏蛋？
the bad guy?
不是
No.
我是说 是的 当年他…
I mean, yeah. He was...
你为什么这么关心他 是因为在电视上看到他？
Why do you care so much? You see his speech on TV or something?
是的 但是…
Yeah, but...
他是我爸
He's my father.
什么？
What?
- 他和我妈 他们… - 行了 我懂
- Him and my mom, they did it. - No, I know...
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
是啊 是啊 是的 在我出生前他弃我妈而去
Yeah. He left my mom before I was born.
我10年前见过他 但我没认出他来
I met him 10 years back but I didn't know it was him.
等我知道时候已经太迟了
By the time I figured it out, it was too late.
然后 这个星期我在电视上又看到他
Then, this week I saw him on TV again...
而且 我去他家找过他
and I came to that house, looking for him...
不过 我到了那里
but by the time I got there...
又迟了
Late again.
虽然我动作很快
For a guy who moves as fast as me...
但好像总是迟到
I always seem to be too late.
我们希望这次不会
Let's hope not this time.
是啊
Yeah.
绝对不会
Seriously.
听我说
Hear me...
这个世界上所有人
inhabitants of this world.
- 怎么回事？- 这是给你们的忠告
- What is that? - This is a message.
好像是教授
I think it's the Professor.
给每个人类和变种人的忠告
A message to every man, woman, and mutant in the world.
你们已经迷失了方向
You have lost your way.
不过 我已归位
But I have returned.
最终审判时刻已到
The day of reckoning is here.
你们所有的建设…
All your buildings...
你们所有的琼楼玉宇…
...all of your towers and temples...
都将倒塌
Will fall.
一个新纪元即将出现
And the dawn of a new age will rise.
你们根本无力反抗…
...for there is nothing you can do...
- 琴 - 阻止即将发生的事
- Jean. - ...to stop what is coming.
琴 如果你能听到 仔细聆听我的声音
Jean, if you can hear me, focus on my voice.
开罗 找到我们 琴
Cairo. Find us, Jean.
找到我们 在开罗 找到我们
Find us. Cairo. Find us.
传递这个讯息只有一个目的
This message is for one reason alone.
告诉你们当中最强的人…
To tell the strongest among you...
拥有最强能力的人
Those with the greatest power...
这个地球将属于你们
this earth will be yours.
那些拥有最强能力的人
Those with the greatest power...
保护那些没有能力的人
protect those without.
这是我给世界的讯息
That's my message to the world.
查尔斯没用超脑发讯息
How was Charles doing that without Cerebro?
长官 是谁在说话？
Sir, what was that voice?
我认得那声音
I know that voice.
是泽维尔 对不对 怎么回事？
It's Xavier, isn't it? What's going on?
- 我们不知道 - 我们不知道 兄弟
- We don't know! - We don't know, bro!
他只是跟我说话
He just spoke to me.
我觉得他是对所有人说话
I think he spoke to everyone.
- 我也能听到 - 不
- I could hear him, too. - No, no...
他刚给我发了一个隐藏的消息
he just sent me a hidden message.
他知道只有我听得到
One he knew only I would hear.
我知道他们在哪里
I know where they are.
嘿
Hey!
有枪声 从哪来的？
We have shots fired! Where's it coming from?
六号牢区发现入侵者
I have intruders in Quad Six.
派遣警备队抓人
Send a security team. Take them out.
发电机室 这值得一试
The generator. It's worth a shot.
库尔特？
Kurt?
那里面有某种动物
There's some kind of animal in there.
不是动物
It's no animal.
是人
It's a man.
他是谁？
Who is he?
他部分记忆被消除了
That part of him as been taken away.
你什么意思？
What do you mean?
我是说他们把他变成某种武器
I mean they turned him into some kind of weapon.
C3组 请回答 找到目标没？
Charlie Three, report. Did you find them?
把它关掉
Shut it down.
开火
Fire!
X武器已逃逸 复诵
Weapon X is loose!
X武器已逃逸
I repeat, Weapon X is loose!
我再重复一遍 X武器已逃逸
你确定那不是动物？
You sure he's not an animal?
- 他在中央大厅 - 第5区发现目标
- He's into the central halls. - Engaging target Sector Five.
我们阻止不了
We can't...
嘿
Hey!
- 他们在干什么？- 这是怎么回事？
- What are they doing? - What's going on?
- 快放我们出去 - 这里发生了什么？
- I just lost feed. - Hey! What's going on here?
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
行动
No!
嘿 留在原地别动
Hey! Stay where you are!
史考特 等等
Scott, wait.
我能帮你
I can help you.
琴
Jean.
罗根 罗根
Logan. Logan.
你对他做了什么？
What'd you do to him?
找到他失去的一段记忆还给他
I found a piece of his past and gave it back to him.
我也只能帮他找到那些
Just the few memories I could reach.
我想以后不会再见到他了
I hope that's the last we've seen of that guy.
库尔特
Kurt.
- 什么？- 什么？
- What? - What?
嘿
Hey.
离开这个…
Stay away from the...
这个什么？
The what?
这 门
The do...
离开这门…
Stay away from the...
离开这门
Get away from the door!
三 二 一
On three. One... two...
我们知道教授在哪里
We know where the Professor is.
我想我们可能有办法离开这里
I think we might have a way out of here.
- 嗯 你一直在忙 - 我们得到了一点帮助
- Well, you've been busy. - We had a little help.
我们走吧
Let's go!
天啊
Jesus!
哦 对不起
Oh, sorry!
这条路
This way!
这本来是宇宙的中心
This was meant to be the center of the universe...
在我被出卖之前
before I was betrayed.
现在
Now...
它将会…
it will be.
太棒了
Nice.
嘿 汉克 你能驾驶它吗？
Hey, Hank, do you think you can fly this thing?
是的 我会搞定的
Yeah, I can figure it out.
各位
Hey, guys.
飞行装
Flight suits.
去搞定你的战机吧
You got your warplane.
准备开战
Let's go to war.
这份天赋…
A gift...
是你先辈留给你的
from the past you left behind...
而同样的你的未来就在眼前
and the future that lies ahead.
运用你的力量 孩子
You will reach down, my son.
深入到地心里
Deep into the earth.
把人类在地上建造的全都给我撕碎
Rip everything they've built from the ground.
彻底清理这个世界
Wipe clean this world.
我们将带领那些幸存者
And we will lead those that survive...
创造更美好的世界
into a better one.
那我呢？
And me?
在你的疯狂计划里我该扮演什么样的角色？
Am I to play a role in this madness?
你可是重中之重
You have the most important role of all.
你害怕吗？
Were you scared?
当年你在华盛顿特区害怕吗？
That day in D.C., were you scared?
不怕
No.
不过我出第一次任务时很怕
But I was scared on my first mission.
那时和朋友坐在像现在这样的飞机上
I was on a plane like this with my friends.
跟你的年纪差不多
About your age.
我们称自己为X战警
We called ourselves the X-Men.
你哥哥当时也在
Your brother was there.
我们都称呼他"浩劫"
We used to call him Havok.
他的能力很难控制 但是…
He was a real handful...but
战斗中他很勇敢
when it came down to it, he was very brave.
那跟你们一起的其他人呢？
What happened to the rest of the kids who went with you?
X战警
The X-Men?
只有汉克和我还活着
Hank and I are the only ones left.
我没能救到其他人
I couldn't save the rest of them.
我说过我不是英雄
I told you, I'm not a hero.
对我们而言你就是英雄
Well, you're a hero to us.
那天在电视上看见你改变了我的一生
Seeing you that day on changed my life.
我也是
Mine, too.
我也是 虽然我还住在我妈的地下室 但是…
I still live in my mom's basement but, you know...
生活中的其他事…
everything else is...
好像还是老样子
It's pretty much the same.
我就是个彻底的失败者
I'm a total loser.
我们现在看到的是一个地磁现象
What we're seeing is a magnetic phenomenon...
比我们在奥斯威辛看到的规模更大
on a much larger scale than what we saw at Auschwitz.
地表层满是地磁元素 铁 镍 钴
The ground is full of magnetic elements. Iron, nickel, cobalt.
而海底表层也同样如此
The ocean's floor is lined with them, too.
此现象已经开始了 来自地心深处
It's already begun at the lowest depths.
陆地能阻挡一阵子 但撑不了太久
Land masses will slow it, but not for long.
最终城市 都市中心
Eventually, cities, urban centers...
自铜器时代造就的一切均将毁灭
anything built since the Bronze Age will be wiped away.
死亡人数将达数十亿
The death toll will be in the billions.
他是在说整个世界都将毁灭
He's talking about the whole goddamn world.
这是怎么回事？大家快出去
你只不过是另一个伪神
You're just another false god.
无论是谁追随了你
And whoever's left to follow you when this all over...
他们终将会再次背叛你
they will betray you again.
你错了 查尔斯
You're wrong, Charles.
在我千百次轮回中 …
For the first time in a thousand lifetimes...
我找到了你
I have you.
我拥有无数天赋 但始终没找到我最需要的
For all my gifts, I have yet to possess the one I needed most.
那就是…
To be...
无所不在
everywhere.
成为…
To be...
每一个人
everyone.
第七大奇观 12点方向
Seventh wonder, twelve o'clock.
教授在金字塔的中间
He has the Professor in the center of the pyramid.
他要将他的意念移转给教授
He's going to transfer his consciousness into the Professor.
如果他得逞了 那他就能控制这世上所有人的心智
If he does that, he'll have the power to control every mind in the world.
那又是怎么回事？
What the hell is that?
那是艾瑞克
It's Erik.
你们协助夜行者潜入金字塔内
You guys help Nightcrawler get into the pyramid.
救出查尔斯 我去对付艾瑞克
Get Charles. I'll take care of Erik.
要怎么通过那里？
How are we gonna get through that?
我可以帮你过去
I can get you in there.
我为了他而来 让我帮你
I came here for him. Let me help you.
其他人去救查尔斯 并带他离开这里
The rest of you, get Charles on this plane and get him out of here.
- 我们不会丢下你的 - 别担心
- We're not leaving without you! - Don't worry.
我们会赶上的
We'll catch up.
坐稳了
Hold on.
汉克 你跟孩子们一起
Hank, you go with the kids.
- 莫伊拉在飞机上等着 - 等一下
- Moira will be waiting on the plane. - Wait.
怎么了？
What?
我们都还不能完全控制自己的能力
Not all of us can fully control our powers.
那就别控制
Then don't.
尽情发挥
You need to embrace them.
大家都这样做
We all do.
去吧 和他们一起
Go. Join the others.
保护我 直到我完成移转
Protect me, until the transference is complete.
前面入口安全
There's an entrance. It's clear.
库尔特 快进去
Kurt! Get in there!
进金字塔 行动
In the pyramid! Move!
快
Go!
把他们分开
Split them up.
不好 教授
Professor...
库尔特 你得快点
Kurt, you have to hurry!
我正在找 这里像个迷宫
I'm trying. It's like a maze in here.
库尔特 不
Kurt, no!
磁场太强 我们没法进去
The magnetic field is too strong. I can't get us in there.
艾瑞克
Erik!
魔形女
Mystique.
我知道你觉得你已经失去了一切
I know you think you've lost everything.
但是 你没有
But you haven't.
你还有我
You have me.
你还有查尔斯
You have Charles.
你还有你不知道的家人
You have more family than you know.
你以前没能保护家人
You never had the chance to save your family before.
但是你现在有了
But you do now.
我来这里就是要告诉你
That's what I've come here to tell you.
那你呢？
And you?
我是你的…
I'm your...
我也是为了我家人而来
I'm here for my family, too.
滚出去 滚出去
Get out. Get out!
滚出去
Get out!
再见了
Auf Wiedersehen.
他支持不住了
We're losing him.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
史考特 戴上眼镜
Scott, glasses on!
我们走
Let's go!
- 锁定 - 出发
- Locked on. - Here we go.
灵蝶
Psylocke!
那是什么鬼东西？
What the hell was that?
库尔特
Kurt.
大家都抓紧夜行者
Everyone, grab hold of Nightcrawler!
我从来没有带过这么多人
I've never done it with this many people.
带我们离开这里
Get us out of here.
库尔特 快点
Kurt, hurry!
库尔特
Kurt!
查尔斯
Charles...
他没事吧？
Is he okay?
他只是筋疲力尽了
It's his energy. He's drained.
滚出去
Get out.
Get out!
教授 教授 没事了 是我们
Professor, it's okay. You're with us.
没事了
It's okay.
我决定回去为他们而战
I'm going to fight for what I have left.
你呢？
Are you?
我看到了许多连你自己都不知道的东西
There's so much more to you than you know.
不只是痛苦和愤怒
Not just pain and anger.
还有许多美好的回忆
There's good, too. I felt it.
你抛下的不仅仅是我
It's not just me you're walking away from.
你有机会成就比自己更伟大的事情
Here, you have the chance to be a part of something much bigger than yourself.
我们需要你 艾瑞克
And it needs you, Erik.
一群废物
Useless.
查尔斯
Charles.
我知道你能听到我的声音
I know you can hear me.
我们仍然联系着彼此
We're still connected.
查尔斯
Charles!
给我出来
Show yourself!
查尔斯
Charles!
快给我出来
Show yourself!
傻小子
Foolish child.
皮特
Peter.
终结他
End him.
瑞雯
Raven.
伟大的英雄
The great hero.
- 我去救他们 - 我和你一起去
- I'm going out there. - I'm going with you.
不
No.
- 他要的是我 - 查尔斯 你不能自投罗网
- It's me he wants. - Charles, you can't give yourself up.
让他找到你 我们就都完了
If he has you, he has us all.
甚至整个世界
The whole world.
你和其他人一样不堪一击
You are feeble. Just like the others.
查尔斯
Charles!
出来
Come!
拯救这群软脚虾
Rescue your weaklings!
用你的命来换他们的
Give your life for theirs!
不
No.
他说的对
He was right.
我和他之间有某种联系
There is still some part of me connected to him.
查尔斯
Charles!
我也可以进入他的脑子里
I can get inside his head.
你要坐视不理吗？
Will you do nothing?
谢谢你让我进去
Thank you for letting me in.
你不是想要我的能力吗？
You want what I have?
你想体会我的感受吗？
You want to feel what I feel?
欢迎来到我的世界
Welcome to my world!
现在你在我的地盘里
You're in my house now!
你地盘不够大
You'll need a bigger house.
你背叛了我
You betray me?
没有
No.
我背叛了他们
I betrayed them.
我们跳下去
Let's jump.
什么？
What?
掩护我
Cover me.
没事了
I got you.
来啊
Come on!
你弱爆了 查尔斯
They lack strength, Charles.
琴
Jean.
过来
Come here.
帮帮…
Help...
我
me.
待在这
Stay here.
他们制不住他
They can't stop him.
琴
Jean.
帮我
Help me!
汉克
Hank!
到此结束 查尔斯 你完了
It's over, Charles. You're finished.
你现在是我的
You're mine now.
你永远不会赢
You will never win.
为什么会这样
And why is that?
因为你只有孤单一人
Because you are alone.
而我不是
And I am not!
让…
Let...
去吧
go.
释放你的力量 琴
Unleash your power, Jean.
不要害怕
No fear.
释放你的力量
Unleash your power!
去吧 琴
Let go, Jean!
琴 去吧
Jean, let go!
他想逃
He's getting away.
结果揭晓
All is revealed.
查尔斯 查尔斯
Charles! Charles!
- 我们已经失去他了 - 查尔斯
- We've lost him! - Charles.
- 他走了 - 不 查尔斯
- He's gone. - No, Charles.
查尔斯…
Charles...
不 他没有
No, he's not.
我还可以感应到他
I can still feel him.
谢谢你 琴
Thank you, Jean.
查尔斯？
Charles?
查尔斯 你知道你在哪里吗？
Charles, do you know where you are?
我在古巴的
I'm on a beach.
海滩上
In Cuba.
和你
With you.
什么海滩？
What beach?
查尔斯·泽维尔
Charles Xavier.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我不应该让你失去那些记忆
I should never have taken those from you.
等一下
Hold on!
我错过了什么？
What did I miss?
看来只有靠上帝的恩典
It seems only by the grace of God...
这恶意的毁坏…
that the ominous destruction...
从世界的一端到另一端 也都停止了
seen from one end of the globe to the other, has stopped.
在今天的汇报中 中情局特派员莫伊拉·玛塔格
At a debriefing today, CIA Special Agent Moira MacTaggert...
向调查委员会报告…
revealed to an investigative committee...
颇为震惊的消息是逃犯艾瑞克·兰谢尔 …
The committee was further stunned to learn that fugitive Erik Lehnsherr...
协助击败了这个强大而难缠的敌人…
aided in defeating this powerful and unknown...
我觉得我们的祈祷应验了
I think our prayers were answered.
谢谢你 总统先生
Thank you, Mr. President.
变种人的潜在破坏力…
The potential destructive power of mutants...
势必掀起另一波争论
...is sure to fuel new controversy and debate...
而此时变种人逐渐在世界各地被接受
at a time when mutants were becoming accepted around the world.
魔形女告诉我 他是你的父亲
Mystique told me he is your father.
你会告诉他吗？
Are you gonna tell him?
可能…
I might...
某天吧
one day.
我想目前 我会在这里待一段时间
I think for now, I'm just gonna stick around here for a while.
我也是
Me, too.
这世界又开始重建武装
The world's already begun rebuilding its arsenals.
这是人的天性 查尔斯
It's human nature, Charles.
我还是抱着希望
I still have hope.
哦 是的
Oh, yes.
"希望"
"Hope."
我没错看瑞雯
I was right about Raven.
甚至我也没看错你
I was even right about you.
那世上其他人呢
What about the rest of the world?
你可曾在半夜里惊醒？
Doesn't it ever wake you up in the middle of the night?
感觉有那么一天他们会来找你…
The feeling that one day they'll come for you...
和你的孩子们
and your children.
确实如此
It does, indeed.
当你醒来以后想些什么？
What do you do when you wake up to that?
我为那些到学校找我麻烦的…
I feel a great swell of pity for the poor soul...
可怜虫感到悲哀
that comes to my school looking for trouble.
我真的没办法说服你留下来吗？
You're sure I can't convince you to stay?
你是心灵大师 查尔斯
You're psychic, Charles.
你可以说服我做任何事情
You can convince me to do anything.
再见 老朋友
Goodbye, old friend.
祝你好运 教授
Good luck, Professor.
忘了你认为你知道的所有事情
Forget everything you think you know.
无论你在学校学到什么…
Whatever lessons you learned in school...
或是你的父母怎么教你的
whatever your parents taught you.
那些都不重要
None of that matters!
你们不再是小孩
You're not kids anymore.
你们也不是学生
You're not students.
你们是X战警
You're X-Men.
(警告禁制区)
(X武器)
(艾塞斯集团)